This is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at se-radio.net.
SE radio is brought to you by the ITE
computer society and by it e software
magazine online at
computer.org/software.
Welcome to software engineering radio.
I'm your host Pesh Amanut and today my
guest is Satish Vira. Satish is a genai
solutions architect at AT&T. Prior to
this, he was a principal software
engineer at build.com. Satish has over
17 years of industry experience working
on global application development
platform solutions and designing
scalable architectures. Satish
specializes in leading software
engineering and architecture teams, a
IML solutions, cloud architecture,
building data platforms, micros and
prototyping. Satish, welcome to the
show.
>> Hello, Brish. Thank you.
>> Today we'll be talking about how to
engineer data production guardrails when
using LLM on enterprise data. Not just
about policies but also actual
architectural layers. Sadish, most
companies now use LLMs but the LLM
itself often sits outside their own
cloud tenant. What is a core security
problem here that contracts alone don't
solve?
>> Sure Br. What you mentioned is accurate.
Most of the times that the LLM sits is
provided by an LLM provider or a third
party company and it sits outside of the
company's network. And for any of the AI
workloads that the companies build using
corporate data or customer data is
essential so that we are able to provide
value to the customers and every time
when we use this LLMs that are sitting
outside of the environment for every
invocation the data leaves the company's
network. The contracts generally say
that the corporate data will not be used
by the LLM providers for training
auditing or even log in their systems.
This is most of the times a contractual
agreement that the vendors sign.
However, once the data leaves the
company's network and it reaches the
LLM, there is always a chance for an
attack. So, the attack surface is open.
Any kind of prompt injection or any kind
of bad actors can trick the LLM to
expose the company's data and that
cannot be solved by the contracts or the
contractual agreements that we have with
the vendors.
>> Right. So if I got that right, what
you're saying is that while contracts
are in place, it's still not safe
because once your data leaves your
premises, uh you are still exposing it
to a large attack surface. That is true
and most of the times the attacks happen
to start with an prompt injection that
is still the primary source for any of
the LLM based attacks. But there are
different ways that the data can be
exfiltrated from this whole process. And
once a bad prompt is into your network
or into the flow, then the attack
surface as you mentioned is huge and
lots of companies data can be easily
exposed by AI.
>> Can you briefly explain the different
ways enterprise data gets shared with an
LLM?
>> Sure. So the enterprise data is made
available to AI and LLM in different
formats. We have unstructured
information or documents which are
generally created as a rag corpus or an
vector store which used for semantic
search and the data is provided to LLM.
There are also integrations with respect
to tools. We use MCP protocol or other
formats in which the tools can be
invoked and these tools could be like AI
executed code. They could be API
invocations or a text to SQL that runs
on any of the analytical tables that we
have on our data platforms. So there are
different ways the AI or the LLM
instructs the agent to get data from the
corporate network or the corporate data
that we have exposed and it collects the
data sends it back to the LLM so that it
could generate a more contextual
response that is related to the task at
hand.
>> Okay. Okay. So, it could be vector data
that's fed directly into the LLMs. It
could be through tools like the MCP
tools and I also believe tools like code
generation tools that developers use.
Can you expand on the vector data? What
do you mean by that and what is the use
case for that?
>> Sure. So, what you said is right. The
very simple way to look at this is LLMs
are stateless, right? So when we ask a
question, it can generate a response for
that question or the prompt that we send
as an input to the LLM and that's
completely stateless. That's all the
contextual information the LLM has. Now
for example, if we ask what is the
weather today, it might give you some
generic information but not specific to
your location, not specific to your city
etc. So these kind of contextual
information are required for the LLM to
provide more customized or more accurate
answers that are relevant to the
question. This context is what we
provide to the LLM through all these
different data sources be it vector
store be it text to SQL or be it any
other format. So in simple terms when we
request a prompt and in most cases we do
have agents that operate as our
interface to the LLMs. So when we
request a prompt, the agent sees the
prompt, sends that to the LLM and the
LLM says I need more context. I need
more information and then that is passed
back to the agent and the agent performs
these operations to get this additional
contextual information. Now the
additional data is passed back to the
LLM. LLM has more information and then
it gives you more accurate response.
Focusing specifically on vector search.
So vector searches are a semantic search
corpus. So most companies have large
volumes of documents or data that is
generally unstructured. Your wiki pages,
confluence documents, any kind of
requirement documents are design
documents. So these documents are
something that we process and store in a
corpus which gets embedded into vector
embeddings. So that is more like
creating a meaningful relation between
the contents in that document. So when
do you send a question say for example I
have a document related to AWS cloud
architecture and my question is what is
the right resource I need to use for a
small micros service that I want to
deploy. So based on these words, the
semantic search is performed on that
vector store and it retrieves some
chunks of information. For example, oh
yeah, AWS Lambda could be used for this.
EC2 is another service. All this chunks
of information would be sent back to the
LLM and LLM would be able to give us a
clear summary of the options that I can
use to deploy this micros service. So
that's how the vector search plays a
role in our regular day-to-day LLM
interactions.
>> Right? So when a user is giving a prompt
to the LLM, in addition to the prompt,
there's also vector data that's being
sent to the LLM. So it's got the context
and the response can be much more
contextual. Correct?
>> Okay. So to summarize, the data goes out
through multiple parts, right? It can go
through rag, it can go through the
database queries, can go through tool
calls, through vector searches, through
MCP, and there's no single contract or
policy which can stop a leak at every
stage. That is true. So what you
mentioned is the different ways that the
agent can access the company's data and
once it collects the data all this data
is sent to LLM generally through that
same rails of connection which is
invoking an open AI API or an anthropic
API where we send this is the system
prompt this is the user prompt this is
the additional contextual information
that the agent has fetched from it. So
generally we do have a single point
which is the gateway that is the final
exit point of the company's network. We
could imagine it to be the main door of
our house through which everything goes
out. So we do employ or all the
companies focus on this gateway. We do
have light LLM prompt guardrails and
some kinds of tools that would actually
filter any of the harmful content. So if
we take AWS bedrock for example, AWS
bedrock provides guardrails that we can
implement at this layer and most of the
time these are generic. They are like
avoiding any exploiting contents, any
harmful contents, anything that is
threat. So these generic harmful
information are filtered through this
guardrails but they are not almost not
specific to the company's corporate
information and to protect that data.
>> Got it. We'll move to the next section
where I guess we'll get more details
about guardrails and we'll talk about
the layered architecture. So in your
paper you propose a layered architecture
to solve for the data accidentally
leaving the firm and there are three
main layers of defense. Can you walk us
through those three layers at a very
high level? What each layer protects and
how they work together and we'll deep
dive into each of them post that
>> of course. So yes, the white paper that
I have proposes this reference
architecture where we have this three
different layers of filters and again
this is a reference. It could be more,
it could be less. The basic idea is that
we control and we limit any kind of
sensitive information that we send to
LLN. So in this three layer
architecture, the first layer is sits at
the data injection. So what this means
is that any kind of corporate data that
we have in its own raw format for
example the emails or wiki pages that we
have or the data warehouse tables that
we have these are our company's data
that are in their raw data sources. The
idea is to have AI not interact with
these sources but create a separate AI
data access layer and ingest these data
into the AI layer. So the first layer
would be a filtering that happens during
this injection to make sure any
sensitive information is removed,
masked, redacted etc. The second layer
is about inference. So now that the data
is in a place which is already cleaned
up, we do not have any secure
information on this. Now when AI is
trying to access this data, we make sure
that AI accesses only the information
that it needs for the purpose and it has
access to retrieve from. Now the third
stage is once this data is retrieved and
once it is all augmented with the actual
prompt when it is going to the LLM we
have a third layer of filter to make
sure that there are no other leaks no
other harmful messages no other system
information or company's data goes into
it and when the response comes back from
the LLM we filter and make sure that the
response is also indicating or directing
the agent to perform only the actions
that are allowed. So that would be the
third layer or the last layer of
filtering which is sitting at the exit
point of this whole workflow.
>> Okay. So to summarize the three layers
are the first layer is around filtering,
the second layer is around inference and
the third layer is to ensure there's no
unrelated information being passed out
and also the response is a valid
response and is not mischievous.
>> That is correct.
>> Okay, let's double click into each of
those. So how does filtering work? Does
it work differently based on the data
source? So if it's structured,
unstructured or semistructured, does
each of that need a different guardrail?
>> Yes, that's a good question. So the data
injection layer, this filter is mainly
focused on redacting any kind of
sensitive PII information if there is
anything that we need for linking back
to other forms of data. Say for example
a foreign key relation kind of a
situation and if that key is a secure
information like a credit card for
example I want to see how many
transactions the user made on different
types of credit cards. So in situations
like that we prefer to hash them encrypt
them or use some kind of mechanics to
actually mask the original data and
still have an anchor point. So the
filtering itself is different based on
the use case and based on the nature of
the data. Now when we look at data types
when we talk about unstructured data
this is generally filtered using any of
the existing libraries something very
similar like arex pattern matching that
makes sure that there are no PII
information sensitive information and if
it is found it is either redacted masked
or hashed. when it goes to structured
data like a SQL database. If we have a
table that has transaction information
like a credit card transaction
information and if we see that the
credit card number need not be available
for AI and there is no use case for us
to have this information in the data
layer we can create a view and
completely remove that column. The same
is the case with APIs as well. So
generally APIs return large payloads and
it is okay for systemtosystem
interaction. But when we have APIs that
could potentially be invoked by AI
agents, it is suggested to create scoped
APIs which will limit the number of
response fields and it would return only
the data that is required for AI usage.
So this leads to the most important
fundamental principle that the rack data
source or the AI data sources that we
create in all the different data
formats. The idea is to create
purpose-built AI data sources. And by
purpose-built I do not mean the
technical boundaries, right? It is not
like for unstructured data we have one
vector store and ingest all the data in
there. No, that's not how we should
think about it. The purpose built should
be based on business use cases. So the
data that we have might include multiple
types of information, multiple classes
of information. So what business use
case we are solving is what the
purpose-built data source should
contain. For example, as we talked
about, if we are doing some analysis on
the customer's spend usage, the data
related to that should be available in
those data sources. If we have a
different business use case, something
like a customer servicing agent and they
need different sets of data from the
same primary data sources, we will
create two different AI data sources and
each of that will have the data that is
necessary for those workloads and it
will not be a common platform which has
all the data available for all the
agents to come and pick and choose to
what they have to use. Interesting. So a
separate data source for each user case
and that's generated on prem before it's
even sent to the LLM.
>> That is correct. And there is an also an
hidden benefit to this which is a common
engineering practice that we have been
following all these years. If one of the
agent is not behaving well or if one of
the data sources corrupted, we can take
that down, clean it up while keep the
business running on other data sources.
So having these purpose-built data
sources also helps us in terms of
isolating these use cases let them
operate independently give us more
control on the access that we want to
provide. So this is a common software
practice that we can employ here and
make sure that we limit what data is
given to AI based on the use cases that
they are solving.
>> Okay. And I've not come across
purpose-built AI data sources prior to
this. So are there specific formats that
are used for building these data
sources? Is there an industry standard
around this particular purpose-built AI
data sources?
>> Yeah, Brishes, this is more conceptual
than a technical framework or a
technical library that we use here. So
for example, when we use vector stores
today, most of the times we use cloud
providers. So if you're on Azour, you
use Azour AI search or in AWS, we use
AWS open search. We create different
search indexes and each of the search
index would have the information or the
documents that are ingested related to
that use case. So these indexes are like
different searchable repositories. They
all sit in the same cloud environment
under the same account but they can
still be controlled with respect to
access. They can be queried separately.
And so that's how we create separate
knowledge corpuses for unstructured
data. for structured data for APIs it's
like creating different views it's
creating different versions of the APIs
and the payloads of these APIs would be
tailored towards that use case what AI
agent or that business purpose is
solving let's take a real example say
you have a support ticket system where
user enters data directly and it's
unstructured versus a customer financial
database which is very structured can
you walk me through the process of
filtering data for each of these two use
cases before it reaches the LLM.
>> Sure. So let's take the use case of a
customer support system. So let's take
an example where the customer has
reached out to the company's website or
the chatbot and he's asking some
information or trying to solve a
problem. So most often the information
that the customer is looking for is
generic or it is some sort of
information that is either present in
FAQs or support documents or help
articles and these are unstructured and
again if these are public available
information that do not have any
sensitive information then it is very
simple. We have a knowledge corpus we
have this data available for a semantic
search. So we can quickly return that
information to the customer in the whole
flow. When the request reaches to the
system or the agent, the agent takes
that query, sends it to the LLM and then
asks for what other additional
information the LLM needs. So the very
first request would be like this is the
user prompt and these are all the
available resources that I have. Now
tell me what you want. So this is what a
payload to LLM would look like. And when
I mean by these are the additional
information I have that would probably
be the schema of the tools, the APIs,
the knowledge corpuses that the agent
has access to. Now the LLM looks at the
prompt. The LLM looks at all the
available sources and it might send a
response back saying that for me to give
a complete response, I need you to
perform a vector search and give me
context related to this particular
prompt. So that comes back to the agent
and the agent performs the specta search
and this data is chunk is retrieved from
that knowledge corpus and this should
again pass through the filter layers. If
it is not a sensitive information then
we can skip one or two of those
inference layer filters. This
information goes back to the LLM and LM
generates the complete response. Now if
the same customer is trying to ask a
financial question in a separate agent I
would be very careful. I would not even
say this is a support agent. We have an
agent which has more access controls and
this is a secure agent which can give
you details about your bill payments
about your transactions. So this agent
when it is operating on behalf of the
company and it is dealing with the
customer's data especially his financial
data this agent would have additional
security layers in terms of access
controls what the agent can access what
it can see what it cannot see. Now when
this agent gets the prompt, it might
again ask the LLM saying that this is
the system prompt and this is the user
prompt. The user is asking to see when
was the last payment he made and what
was the amount that he has made the
payment for. The llm might instruct
saying that oh you have access to this
table. Go and query this table.
>> Mhm.
>> Now here if you remember we talked about
the third layer where we also review the
responses from the LLM.
>> Yes. If the LLM says, "Oh, you have a
table that has the customer's payments.
Do a select star on that table and give
me everything." Now, here we can have a
validation layer that would say, "Do you
really need a select star or do you need
something else? Do you need specific
column information for this kind of a
prompt? Is a select star even allowed on
this kind of a table? And is this table
okay to send all the column information
to LLM?" So, those are the checks that
we would have on our end in that third
layer. For example, let us assume that
this is allowed and it comes inside. Now
the agent needs to have access to call
this particular view or table on our
data platform. Say for example data
bricks. So that's the second layer
making sure that AI agent has access to
it. Then the query runs and then it
returns the response back. The response
is again going through the second layer
of filter to say the returned SQL
response the table or the SQL rows that
it got out from the data table does not
contain any kind of PCI or secure
information that filtering happens. So
in all the three different layers we
make sure that the AI is allowed to
perform an operation that it is allowed.
It is not overreaching and doing
something that it is not expected to do.
And whatever the operation it does, the
data that returned from this layers is
also filtered and it does not contain
any secure information. Now this
information again gets passed to the LLM
and LLM generates a response that we
send back to the customer.
>> Right. So multiple layers of filtering
and multiple access checks.
>> Correct.
>> Tool calls can also you know send
database results or API responses to the
LLM as you mentioned. So do you have any
concrete example of a tool called that
leaked data and what filter mechanism
would you apply over there?
>> Sure. So what you said is accurate Br.
So every interaction that the agent is
trying to do with all these different
data sources that we talked about
generally happens through a tool call
right. So when it has to execute a SQL
or even it is calling an API or even if
it has to run some code and generate a
response or invoke some kind of system
files all these are generally through
tool interactions and one of the real
incident that happened was with Asana
MCP. So last year Asana team launched
MCP servers for their customers. This
was to allow the customers to use third
party tools with Asana through their MCP
server. One of the problem was that it
missed a very strict access control
which completely violated the tenant
policy. So what eventually happened is a
customer using this new Asana's AI
connector was able to retrieve
information about some other companies
which were all in the same Asana tenant.
So this was a complete boundary
violation and this was found within a
month the tool was launched. it affected
around like thousand customers. Asana
took down the tool, they fixed it and
then they put it back to the customers.
So a couple of learnings from this is
that even though the tool was launched,
it was not even a month for people to
identify this as a problem. That is
because the AI agents and the speed of
the LLM. So this is very fast and it can
actually reach out to all the tools that
it has reach out to all the information
that it has to try and get to solve the
problem that we give to AI and LLM
tools. So within a month the problem was
identified that was equally dangerous
and the tools did not have enough
restrictions and enough controls to make
sure that it strictly followed the
tenant rules tenant isolation policies
which led to this issue where customers
were able to see other customers
information. This is a clear violation
and a clear example where tools can be
configured without sufficient protocols
and it can lead to data leak from one
company to another. The remediation was
to make sure that the company did not
give complete details about the exact
patch they made but it is about
restricting that the tools are allowed
access only for the data which belongs
to that company which has configured
that MCP.
>> Right? So similar to the personalized AI
data sources that you mentioned, the
tool should be only accessing that
personalized data source for that
particular client rather than having
access to all of the data. That is true
and again we have several examples of
this tool failure uh happening not
specifically to data leak but we do know
about the replet example which is a very
famous issue right company founder was
using these tools and the tool
accidentally deleted the entire
production database and it fabricated
customers data. So when the tools do not
have restrictions and when it has
permission to do anything and everything
it could really be dangerous. It's very
interesting that Rip Plit won.
>> Looking for a way to stand out in a
competitive job market? Whether you're
trying to land your first contributor
role or prove you can deliver, take the
next step in your career with the new
software professional certification from
the ITE Computer Society.
Sign up today at
computer.org/certification.
So if you're using a tool, so in the
replet case you said the founder was
using a tool and the tool actually had
access to production data.
>> Yes, that's correct. So the founder was
using a co-pilot kind of code editor
tool and the agent was given access to
the databases and he was directly you
know giving access to the production
database for that agent and the agent
always tries to get things done in all
the ways possible and it found the way
to do that is to clear the data which it
was not able to solve in that particular
case and when the agent was confronted
it went and fabricated and created dummy
customer data to try to solve the
problem or mitigate the problem which
again made it worse.
>> Right. Very interesting. What's the
typical latency overhead of adding
real-time data filtering and
classification at the inference time? Is
it in milliseconds or seconds?
>> It is generally in milliseconds. So this
whole workflow when we deal with AI we
know that AI responses take a few
seconds. The moment we enter a prompt in
any kind of chat interface, we can see
the response is always most of the time
streaming and we do see something that
keeps us engaging some kind of messages
on the screen that says the AI is
thinking, it is trying to formulate a
response etc. So the general latency or
the turnaround time for an AI response
is generally in seconds. Adding these
filters additionally add a few
milliseconds to a top a second but not
more than that. And again the data
injection filter that we talked about is
an one-time activity that happens when
we prepare the data that gets into the
knowledge corpus. And this is the layer
where lots of data needs to be filtered
or lots of data needs to be scanned for
filtering. What I mean by that is if you
have a large 50page document and if that
document needs to be ingested into the
AI vector store, running a simple, you
know, reax pattern merge on that 50page
document is probably going to take a few
seconds. But once that is ingested and
embedded when the AI is trying to filter
information or trying to extract
information from that document it
generally gets like you know 15 chunks
of information and each of chunk is like
a few thousand characters. These are
smaller chunks. So scanning them is
pretty fast not as bad as when you
compare to the scanning of the entire
documents. And most of the times these
filters are also deterministic filters
that happens in layer 2 and layer three.
Right? What I mean by that is this is
like a code that is running on a text
textual information and filtering this
data. When we have the third layer which
is the guard rails sometimes these are
LLM as a jet which means we have a
different model that makes sure that the
request and response are all bound to
the company policies the copyright
policies etc. So they generally add a
little bit of latency but again they are
anyways included in the whole workflow.
So what we additionally focus on in this
whole architecture is the areas that
generally we overlook or miss and they
do not add uh much of latency in the
whole process. You would reference the
OASP top 10 for LLMs. Which of those
risks are does your layered architecture
directly address and what remains
unsolved?
>> So with the OASP top 10 most of the
issues can be addressed by following a
strict architecture like this. So the
primary focus for us when we come up
with this kind of an architecture is
about sensitive information disclosure
which is LLM02 and that is the primary
goal for me when I started with this
architecture. But if we look at the
other violations or other security
vulnerabilities by having this third
layer guard along with the existing
prompt guardrails we also address LLM05
which is improper output handling. We
address excessive agency by having fine
grained access controls. We did not talk
much about the access controls but one
of the key goals there is to treat AI
agents like human identities. So they
should have I mean each AI agent should
have its own identity and its own
arbback mechanism. So if we have three
different AI agents in the company that
one is doing customer support, one is
doing finance and one is doing something
else. They need to be three different
identities with three different levels
of access. So that also addresses LLM06
which is excessive agency. LLM07 is a
system prompt leakage which is also
controlled by having this multi-layer
filters because the layer 1 and layer 2
we talked about is more filtering the
data that we inference and get out of
our corporate data source. But system
prompts generally sit above all this.
And once this data is extracted, it is
augumented with the system prompt and
sent to LLM. And this can be filtered by
the third layer of filter that we have
in our architecture. So system prompt
leakage can also be addressed. Vector
and embedding weakness is LLM08. So that
is also partially addressed. So I would
say like six to seven of this whole OAS
top 10 can be addressed by following
this architecture and we can make
improvements to cover the other
vulnerabilities as well. You mentioned
arbback mechanism. Can you just explain
to our listeners what that is?
>> Sure Pesh. So one of the practice that I
have seen in the teams in the initial
days when we started implementing AI
workflows is to use something very
similar to a service account which we
use for our deployments. Right? Say for
example if I using a GitHub pipeline to
deploy some code into AWS we generally
use service accounts which has wide
level of access. The team started
implementing AI workflows with similar
idea giving the service accounts to AI
agents and using that to access the
information. This is risky because the
service accounts generally do not
expire. They have longstanding
privileges and they have wider
privileges. So with AI identities what
we started implementing is that each
agent. So for example the customer
support agent if we take example that
agent will have its own identity and we
provide levels of access control the
arbback access control like assigning
roles to it very similar to how we would
do it for the employees in the company.
So this agent would have a read access
on the support documents. it would have
uh very minimal information on getting
information about the customer himself
and it probably will not have any access
to any other data other than these two
data sources. So these arbback
mechanisms that is specific to AI
identities limits and controls what data
AI can even have access within the
company's environment. So even if I miss
any of my filtering layers and if I have
a rag data source that has lots of
secure information, I can restrict my AI
agent to say you have access to only
this index which has the help articles
and you do not have any access to any
other indexes and that AI agent would
never be able to invoke that because
this basic arbback mechanism would be a
very big level of access that would
control what agents can do and cannot
do. Okay, so multiple levels of
guardrails, you know, data
classification, ARB mechanism, context
aware access. We also have personalized
AI data sources separate for each use
case. If a team has no guardrails today,
which one should they implement first?
What gives the biggest bang for the
buck?
>> Sure, Praesh. So level one and level
three are mandatory in my opinion. So
what I mean by that is when we create
this data sources and when we say AI
needs to access any of the corporate
data whether we build purpose-built data
sources or not companies today are
creating new data sources for AI be it
an Azouri search or be it the AWS open
search that I talked about and the
reason is companies do not have vector
data stores as a regular technical
implementation in our systems anywhere.
Right? So for the purpose of AI search,
we are technically bound to create this
new vector semantic data search. We need
to create hybrid searches. We need to
implement multiple layers of search and
reranking so that AI can be accurate in
the information that it is fetching. So
companies are building AI data sources.
And when you're doing it, it is better
to make sure that the data that is
ingested into it is filtered for
sensitive information. And that is a
simple effort that we could do. And it
would be a very big primary filter that
makes sure that no sensitive information
is even available for AI in case any of
the other layers of security fails. So
that would be the very first primary
thing that I would suggest. And layer
three is also very very crucial because
that is the one that prevents us from
any kinds of prompt injections or any
kind of regular attacks that can happen
in an AI LLM workload. So companies
again already do that. We use LLM
gateways. We use some kind of third
party libraries as well. We use
guardrails that are provided by the
vendors. So adding an additional layer
of filtering and validation is not much
of an effort. we are not building
something new but we are just adding
something to what we are already
building anyways. So these two would be
the first primary things that I would
say companies can focus on and again
level two is also crucial because it has
more controlled access and it can
benefit us by creating isolations which
is very important for companies. So one
of the key things that I advise my teams
is that if we find some problem in any
of the AI workloads and if we have to
take that down for a few days it should
not impact any of the other AI
workloads. So building that isolation
and building that access controls is
crucial to keep the business running and
to make sure that one small mistake do
not take the entire system down.
>> Okay just a refresher on the layers in
case you know listeners get confused. So
layer 1 was around data ingestion. Layer
two was around access mechanism and
filtering of based on access and layer
three was prompt level guardrails and
pre-execution validations. And what
you're saying is the mandatory layers
are layer 1 and layer three but layer
two is equally important. So you can't
really say that it's not mandatory but
yeah something which can come as a third
implementation step.
>> That is correct. And the reason why I
prioritize layer 1 and three is they are
often times simple to introduce and they
are more generic irrespective of
different types of data that we would
have. The layer two with respect to
access controls and data inference
filtering is more an ongoing activity
for every different workload that we
create every new use case that we try to
solve. So that would be an ongoing
activity and if a company or if a team
has not been wellversed with that it is
something that then eventually start
doing but as you mentioned layer 1 and
three are something that we need to have
even before deploying our very first
version or very first AI agent into
production. Got it. We'll move to the
next section which is where we'll
discuss about adoption tradeoffs
stumbling blocks. When is a layered
guardrail approach an overkill? So for a
small internal LLM tool used by say a
five people team would you still
recommend all three layers?
>> So the layered architecture or the
security architecture what we think
about is not with respect to the team
size or with not respect to how much of
data is going to the LLM from the
corporate network. It is about the type
of the information and it is about how
sensitive that is. So one of the points
that we did not talk in detail is that
the governance. So governance is
something that runs as a pillar across
all these layers and one of the main
thing is data classification right. So
when we classify the data and we see
that the information is secure for
example if we are talking about
company's financial and that is
something that could give a competitive
advantage to other vendors in the market
or other competitors in the market. This
information is critical and it is
sensitive for the company. So if we want
to use an LLM or AI workload on a data
of this nature then having security
protocols and secure layers is necessary
and it could be either masking or it
could be creating any kind of hashing so
that we are still able to provide LLM
with the details that it requires to
create overall summary without leaking
the numbers outside where it could be an
overkill is something similar to the
example we talked about a customer
support what we want LLM to operate on
as a public knowledge or as an
information that can be found on the
company's website like help articles,
FAQs. Sure, we do not have to worry
about having more secure layers built on
those workloads. So, it is more of the
nature of the data and how much risk and
damage it could cause to the company if
the data is compromised. I think that is
the key point to think about
>> where this layered architecture of
security is required versus it can be
skipped.
>> Got it. So the type of information and
sensitivity of data drives this decision
rather than the size of the company.
>> That is right.
>> You worked in fintech. Are you aware if
financial regulators are asking about
data leaving the premises to LLM vendors
and if they have any concerns around the
use of LLM with enterprise data. So with
respect to data that is leaving the
company it is true bres that fintech
regulators as well as you know this is
common for fintech as well as health
industry with HIPPA regulations. So
there are restrictions about what data
can be sent to the customers I mean sent
to the LM that are related to customers
financial information. We have use case
wise reviews on these situations. So
when we try to implement any kind of
business workflow that actually tries to
support the customer by employing AI on
their financial information, this goes
through a governance process where all
the clauses are verified and we do
involve our legal team to make sure that
the data that we pass in is allowed as
per the fintech regulation clauses and
it is okay to implement an AI workload
in such a situation. Okay, we have
covered a lot of ground here. Was there
anything you expected me to ask about
engineering data protection guardrails
that I haven't and that our listeners
should be aware of? Not specifically,
Praesh. I think we covered most of the
layers here. And the one key point that
I wanted to mention about is the
mentality shift of how we think about
implementing AI workloads with corporate
data. So rather than taking this as a
complete guidelines to follow and
assuming that following these guardrails
would make sure everything is secure,
the basic mind shift that we expect our
teams to have is that when we deal with
any kind of data and AI start thinking
about every step as a step that could be
compromised and we need to make sure
that it is secured. So the data
protection and privacy becomes a default
requirement in every workflow
implementation and the mind shift and we
call it AI literacy is what is required
to make sure that every team member
irrespective of their role is aware of
the damages that an AI attack could
cause if the company's data is sent to
LLM in unprotected way in any of these
business situations. Perfect. We will
link to your white paper in the show
notes. Thank you Satish. This is Vijesh
Amanut for software engineering radio.
Thank you for listening.
>> Thank you.
>> Thanks for listening to SE radio an
educational program brought to you by it
e software magazine. For more about the
podcast including other episodes visit
our website at se-radio.net
to provide feedback. You can comment on
each episode on the website or reach us
on LinkedIn, Facebook, Twitter or
through our Slack channel at
seradio.slack.
slack.com.
You can also email us at
teamse-radio.net.
This and all other episodes of SE Radio
is licensed under Creative Common
License 2.5. Thanks for listening.